<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on 123k.pl</title>
    <link>https://123k.pl/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on 123k.pl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 10:43:07 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://123k.pl/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Geo-Locations</title>
      <link>https://123k.pl/posts/geo-location-sse-stream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 10:43:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://123k.pl/posts/geo-location-sse-stream/</guid>
      <description>Streaming Server Experiments My first tests with streaming geo-locations from mongodb to a webclient started. The results are pretty promising and I even have two calls in production already.
Mosty - Spring-Boot Webflux My first try will be a Spring-Boot application named Mosty (which is of course a small village nearby and home of the infamous sandpit). The result for now is basically a copy and paste from tutorials and stack-overflow - but it just work and the first stream of points is already consumed by my new static homepage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year New Start</title>
      <link>https://123k.pl/posts/new-year-new-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 19:42:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://123k.pl/posts/new-year-new-start/</guid>
      <description>Back in Business Hello there, I&amp;rsquo;m Back in Business (jak EPMD!) - only after three years of effective inactivity I decided to re-active this blog again. As I really did not prepare any content 1 , I can only start with some small notes.
Disaster and Recovery So in September 2018 I found out, that my server where the 123k project runs did not respond any more. I went to the fabulous Hetzner site and found out, that it just does not boot any more because of ZFS file system corruption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Many Clickable Points on a Leaflet Map With Leaflet.glify</title>
      <link>https://123k.pl/posts/many-clickable-points-on-a-leaflet-map-with-leaflet-glify/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 09:29:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://123k.pl/posts/many-clickable-points-on-a-leaflet-map-with-leaflet-glify/</guid>
      <description>Problem As seen in the post before we collected some 12.000 points which we want to display on a leaflet map. Every attempt to put that many points on one map failed. Firefox completely stopped working, chrome did a little bit better and stayed responsive, but that was not a solution at all.
Solution I pretty much tried everything L.geoJSON layer with points and polygons. Where polygons would have been a solution maybe, but you can not tell leaflet to just draw the corners of the polygons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Coverage Map With Mongodb</title>
      <link>https://123k.pl/posts/build-a-coverage-map-with-mongodb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 19:38:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://123k.pl/posts/build-a-coverage-map-with-mongodb/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When I started with my personal bike-track homepage at 123k.org a few years ago I decided to put all my tracks in a MongoDB. The model I use is very simple. I have a class Route which holds meta-data about the track and a class TrackPoint which represents a point and has a foreign key to the respective track (of course). After some years I have 612827 track-points. So 600k entries is not &amp;lsquo;big-data&amp;rsquo; exactly, but it is too much to be displayed on a leaflet map at once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Show routes to current geohash</title>
      <link>https://123k.pl/posts/show-routes-to-current-geohash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://123k.pl/posts/show-routes-to-current-geohash/</guid>
      <description>The Plan My geohashing alert2016-01-13 15:28-system at 123k.org shows the current geohash for my home graticule. The plan is to the nearest route which passes by.
Finding Something As mentioned earlier I have all points i ever visited in a collection. This collection holds a geospatial index. Therefore I can issue mongo queries with the $nearSphere command. This command finds the first points from a given location.
 So this just works.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>